Daily**Writing**Tips
--------------------

Privacy Policy
==============

We are committed to respecting the privacy rights of visitors and users of this website. We created this Privacy Policy (this “Policy”) to explain what information we collect from you, how we secure that information, and under what conditions we share your information with others. This Policy only applies to this website, and not other platforms you can access through the website such as social media and third party websites.

1\. NOTICE CONCERNING CHILDREN.

Any website “directed at children under 13” must undertake certain compliance steps pursuant to the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act \[15 U.S. Code § 6502\] and COPPA Rule \[16 CFR Part 312\]. This website is directed at adults, not children.

2\. PERSONAL INFORMATION COLLECTED.

A. Information Collection: We may require you to provide us with certain information that personally identifies you (“Personal Information”). Personal Information includes the following categories of information: (1) Contact Data (such as your name and e-mail address). If you communicate with us by e-mail, or otherwise contact us, any information provided in such communication may be collected as Personal Information.

B. Modification or Removal Process: You may opt-out of our email list using the provided link in any email message. You may also contact us to request we remove any content you’ve submitted to the website; a request which we will approve or deny in our sole discretion.

C. Privacy Policy Updates: If we modify or update this Policy, we will notify you by posting a notice on the website and by sending you an electronic message indicating as much if we have an email address for you. You may reject the update by discontinuing your use of the website.

D. Do Not Track Signals: Certain jurisdictions require that we disclose whether we acknowledge “do not track” signals issued by browsers or privacy software. We do not respond to such signals at this time.

E. Google Tracking. We use certain Google programs to help us analyze the traffic to this website and improve our marketing efforts. Such programs may include, but are not limited to, Google Analytics Remarketing, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, and Integrated services that require Google Analytics to collect data via advertising cookies and identifiers. You may opt out of this tracking by visiting https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/ and http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/.

F. Third Party Tracking. We allow third-party companies to collect certain anonymous information when you visit this website. These companies, including Google, may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g. ads you click versus those you don’t, the type of browser you use, etc.) in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice visit the NAI at http://www.networkadvertising.org. To opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/ which will automatically detect and opt-out of a majority of the tracking programs.

G. Google Adsense. We allow third party vendors, including Google Adsense, to use cookies to serve ads based on your prior visits to this website or other websites. These companies use of advertising cookies enables them and their partners to serve ads to you based on the websites you visit online. Google will use a Double Click cookie to track your actions in this regard. You can opt out of this program by visiting https://www.google.com/settings/ads or by other third parties by visiting http://www.aboutads.info/choices/.

H. Amazon Affiliate. This website is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com.

I. Other Affiliate Programs. This website participates in third party website programs in addition to Amazon.com from time to time. If you click a link to another site, make sure to review the privacy policy of that site to gain an understanding of how your information is collected, stored, and used.

3\. COOKIES AND TRAFFIC DATA COLLECTED.

We automatically track and collect the following categories of information when you visit this website including: (1) IP addresses; (2) domain servers; (3) types of computers accessing the website; and (4) types of web browsers used to access the website (collectively “Traffic Data”). Traffic Data is anonymous information that does not personally identify you but is helpful for marketing purposes and for helping us improve your experience when accessing this website.

4\. USE OF INFORMATION COLLECTED

A. Our Use Of Information: We use your Personal Information to interact with and market to you as well as comply with various laws as detailed herein. Please read this Section 4 carefully.

B. Sharing Personal Information: We share certain categories of information we collect from you in the ways described in this Policy. We share Contact Data with our business partners who assist us by performing core services (such as hosting, billing, email distribution, or data storage and security) related to our operation of this website. If you do not want us to share your Personal Information with any third parties, please contact us, but please understand that such a request will eliminate your ability to access certain areas of the website.

C. Use of Contact Data. We use your Contact Data to provide you with administrative communications. We also use your Contact Data to send you commercial emails highlighting products and services that may be of interest to you. These email communications may contain messages, advertisements, and affiliate links promoting third parties and third party products.

D. Sale of Information: Should we decide to sell all or part of our core business or this website at some point in the future, your Personal Information will be included as an asset in the transfer of the business to the new owner.

5\. MARKETING

A. Third Party Advertising Cookies. We may use certain third-party vendors, including Google, who use cookies to serve ads to you while on our website based on your prior visits to this website and other websites. You can opt out of personalized advertising by Google by visiting https://www.google.com/settings/ads or by other third parties by visiting http://www.aboutads.info/choices/.

B. Remarketing and Retargeting. We may use Facebook or other third party remarketing or retargeting platforms to market our business. These companies use cookies to track you across the Internet including websites you visited before visiting us and after you leave. Once you leave this website, Facebook, and the other third party platforms we may use, will show you advertisements from us as appropriate. You may opt out of the remarketing and retargeting platforms we currently use or may use in the future by visiting the following links:

• Facebook – \[https://www.facebook.com/ads/website\_custom\_audiences/\] • Google – \[http://www.google.com/settings/ads\]

6\. INFORMATION SECURITY

A. Confidentiality and Security of Personal Information: Except as otherwise provided in this Policy, we will keep your Personal Information private and will not share it with third parties, unless such disclosure is necessary to: (a) comply with a court order or other legal process; (b) protect our rights or property; or (c) enforce the legal documents applicable to the website.

B. Security. This website has reasonable security measures in place including Secure Sockets Layer technology. Unfortunately, we make no promises about our ability to prevent any such loss or misuse of your Personal Information since preventing hacking is nearly impossible.

7\. AREAS BEYOND OUR CONTROL

A. Public Information: We may allow you to interact with others from time to time in the comments section as well as our social media pages. Please understand that any information disclosed in these areas becomes public information. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your Personal Information.

B. Third Party Websites: The website contains links to other websites. We have no control over the terms and privacy policies of said sites. Please make sure to view the policies of those sites before proceeding.

8\. iThemes Security Security Logs The IP address of visitors, user ID of logged in users, and username of login attempts are conditionally logged to check for malicious activity and to protect the site from specific kinds of attacks. Examples of conditions when logging occurs include login attempts, log out requests, requests for suspicious URLs, changes to site content, and password updates. This information is retained for 60 days.Who we share your data with This site is scanned for potential malware and vulnerabilities by the iThemes Site Scanner. We do not send personal information to the scanner; however, the scanner could find personal information posted publicly (such as in comments) during the scan.

How long we retain your data Security logs are retained for 60 days.

Where we send your data This site is part of a network of sites that protect against distributed brute force attacks. To enable this protection, the IP address of visitors attempting to log into the site is shared with a service provided by ithemes.com. For privacy policy details, please see the [iThemes Privacy Policy](https://www.liquidweb.com/about-us/policies/privacy-policy/).

9\. Comments and Akismet

We collect information about visitors who comment on Sites that use our Akismet anti-spam service. The information we collect can include the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).

10\. CONTACT INFORMATION

If you have any questions about this Policy or our practices related to this website, please contact us at [\[email protected\]](https://www.dailywritingtips.com/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection).

#### Advertising.

This Site is affiliated with CMI Marketing, Inc., d/b/a CafeMedia (“CafeMedia”) for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site, and CafeMedia will collect and use certain data for advertising purposes. To learn more about CafeMedia’s data usage, click here [www.cafemedia.com/publisher-advertising-privacy-policy](http://www.cafemedia.com/publisher-advertising-privacy-policy)

Search

Search

Categories
----------

2024 © Daily Writing Tips, a Found First Marketing company. All rights reserved.

Review Your Cart

0

Discount

Add Coupon Code

 Apply

Subtotal

Total Installment Payments

Bundle Discount

0
